David Dietrich

Software Developer Waterloo, Ontario March 2023
david.drich@gmail.com
github.com/godares79
linkedin.com/in/david-drich

Objective

Self-directed learner seeking a Senior Software Developer position in a fast-paced and challenging environment. Thrives in ambiguity. Proven tech lead. 10+ years of experience. Strong collaboration skills and several years of experience mentoring junior developers.

Work Experience

Google
Software Engineer - Google Cloud

USA/Japan/Canada

Jan 2022 - Current

- Designed and built Terraform and Kubernetes configurations, release pipeline, and probers for single-tenant GKE clusters.
- Drove decision to migrate Cloud source-control product from GCP VMs to GKE, reducing the work required for the eventual public release by 3+ eng months.

Software Engineer - Android Platform

Mar 2020 - Jan 2022

- Created new configuration system and migrated existing test definitions, resulting in an over 10x reduction in test definition LOC.
- Designed and built performance testing suite for Android platform modules, catching performance regressions much earlier in the development lifecycle.

Software Engineer, Tools and Infrastructure - Android Google Maps

Jan 2014 - Mar 2020

- Lead team tasked with improving developer velocity. We significantly improved test flakiness and test performance, reducing wall time of code submissions from 45 minutes to 25 minutes.
 Resulting in 6+ eng-months of waiting time saved per year.
- Refactored build configurations for Android Google Maps to improve readability and build performance, reducing average wall time of incremental builds by approximately 5 minutes.
- Designed and built conformance test infrastructure and test suite for Android Auto. This suite is shipped to OEMs for verification of their Android Auto implementation in vehicles.

University of Waterloo
Research Assistant: Formal Methods Lab
Sept 2011 - May 2013
University of Alberta
Edmonton, AB
Web Developer
May 2011 - Sept 2011
Energy Navigator Inc.
Calgary, AB
Junior Software Developer
May 2009 - Aug 2010

Education

University of WaterlooWaterloo, ONM.Math Computer Science2011 - 2013University of AlbertaEdmonton, ABB.Sc. Computer Science2006 - 2011

Technical Skills

Frameworks: Bazel, Kubernetes, GCP, Terraform, Git, Jenkins, Cloud Build, Protobuf, Linux, Git Languages: Python, Java, GCL, Bash